SOFTWARE ENGINEER · WEB AND MOBILE

12866 N. Bloomington Loop, Oro Valley AZ 85755

🛮 (520)-906-6278 | 🗷 cferris@gmail.com | 🏕 claytonferris.com | 🖸 theshortcut | 🛅 clayferris | 💆 @clayferris

Summary_

Full stack and mobile application development. Working with JavaScript for over a decade, spanning across React, Angular, Backbone, jQuery and vanilla JS. Built and deployed APIs using REST methodologies and more recently GraphQL in Scala and Node.js. Mobile app development for both iOS and Android using Swift, Typescript, Objective-C, Java, Xamarin, and React Native.

DevOps experience with Terraform, SaltStack, Ansible and CloudFormation. Continuous deployment using Circle CI, Codefresh, Gitlab CI, Docker, Kubernetes and Argo. Passionate about lowering developer friction for builds and deployment to enable shipping code early and often.

Interested in finding creative solutions to hard problems, continuing to learn new technologies and building fun and engaging products.

Work Experience

Weedmaps Remote

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER Aug. 2017 - PRESENT

- Incremental migration from AngularJS to React + Next.js
- · Led adoption of Typescript in a large codebase
- Implemented Cypress-based integration testing
- · Worked to improve our CI/CD pipeline and into a gitops flow

SpinGo Remote

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2012 - Aug. 2017

- AWS Infrastructure setup and management with SaltStack.
- Transitioned a monolithic PHP application to scalable Scala microservices with AngularJS and React / Redux client side
- Data integration with Salesforce
- Swift-based iOS app development (live in the AppStore)
- ETL Pipeline for data analysis using Vertica and Tableau

Contract / Passion Projects Remote

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Aug. 2012 - PRESENT

- Android and iOS app using React Native and Redux (WeVyte)
- Local business website development (Beyond Bread)

Raytheon Missile SystemsTucson, AZDeveloperDec. 2007 - Aug. 2011

• Front end web development for both raytheon.com and internal intranet

- Implemented JavaScript components and plugins integrated into Oracle CMS
- Led the migration away from Flash to modern and open web technologies
- Built the company's first mobile and responsive microsites

Spin Media Marketing Provo, UT

Jun. 2006 - Aug. 2011

• Lead developer for many internal and client web applications

Lead developer for many internal and client web apprications

 Delevers Beile We advanced Developers and the control of the control o

Ruby on Rails, Wordpress and Drupal development

Soularium Studios Alpine, UT

AUDIO ENGINEER Dec. 2005 - Dec. 2006

- Audio recording, mixing, and mastering on a high-end Pro Tools DAW
- Troubleshooting and maintenance of studio computers and equipment
- · Serving and hosting created audio to clients across the world

BYU Media Arts Lab Provo, UT

ADMINISTRATOR Jan. 2004 - Dec. 2005

- Managed audio and video editing workstations
- Deployed a web-based equipment checkout system
- Trained students on industry-standard software
- Set up and maintained an Xgrid/Xserve system for streamlining media workflows

Skills

TECHNICAL DIRECTOR

Languages JavaScript (Node.js & Browser), Scala, Swift, Objective-C, Ruby, Kotlin, Sass

JS Libraries React, Next.js, MobX, Redux, React Native, Express

Services & Protocols PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, RabbitMQ, Redis, MongoDB, Pusher, Airbrake, WebSockets, Swagger, GraphQL

Amazon Web Services EC2, S3, SES, CloudFormation, CloudFront, Kinesis, Redshift, DynamoDB

Infrastructure & Automation Terraform, Kubernetes, SaltStack, Ansible, Docker, CircleCI

Education

Brigham Young University

Provo. UT

B.A. IN MEDIA ARTS STUDIES

Sep. 2000 - Apr. 2006

Honors & Awards

HACKATHONS

2015 1st Place, CactusHack
 2013 1st Place, Startup Weekend
 3alt Lake City, UT

Recommendations.

Tim Harper SpinGo

Cheif Technology Officer direct manager

Clay is great to work with! He's a tremendously talented and proactive engineer who cares deeply about his work. One specific "shiny feature" of Clay is his ability to ask the right questions early on in the work-breakdown process, which frequently has directed attention to parts of a spec that may need to go back to the drawing board; this has really contributed to our ability to successfully execute a spec.

Ashton Snelgrove SpinGo

SOFTWARE ENGINEER worked in the same group

Clay is a pleasure to work with. He is knowledgeable and hard working. I could always rely on Clay to get the job done and help with any problems I had. His code was consistently well written, and he always drove the business forward towards our goals. He was an excellent communicator, and helped make the team what it was. I'd love to work with him again.

Jordan Davis SpinGo

Cheif Operating Officer worked in different groups

Clay is the secretest secret weapon in software development. He is incredibly connected to the pulse of new technology, and knows all about the latest devices, platforms, coding languages, and what is possible with the combination of all of them. He also has a great taste for music and entertainment in general, which obviously feeds his polished front-end design skills. I never questioned the integrity of the code Clay built, and any modifications were prompt and thorough (which is tricky to do). I have my fingers crossed that one day I get to work with Clay again.

Interests

In no particular order: functional programming, reading (most recently books by Patrick Rothfuss, Brandon Sanderson and Scott Lynch), music (playing drums & guitar), racquetball, home automation, machine learning, soccer, film, sound recording, 3D printing & prototyping.